哦 見鬼...
Oh, bollocks.
我們遇到一點問題
We've got a problem.
- 一場網絡攻擊？
- 是的首相大人
- A cyber attack? - Yes, prime minister.
唉 我喝了兩瓶紅酒 吃了半包安眠藥好不容易才睡著...
Ahh... Took me two bottles of wine and half a packet of sleeping pills to finally nod off.
然後你把我吵醒 就因為某個胖手指的黑客偷了你的密碼？
And you wake me because some fat-fingered hacker's pinched your pin number?
實際上問題要比您說的更嚴重一些 首相大人
Well, it's a little more serious than that, prime minister.
- 嗯？
- 我們所有在職特工的身份都暴露了
- Hmm? - The identities of every one of our serving agents have been exposed.
什麼？
What?
- 誰在發動這場攻擊？
- 我們還不確定夫人
- Who's doing this? - We're not sure, ma'am.
所以在我主辦自己的第一場 G12峰會的一周前
So one week before I host my first G12 summit,
整個英國的安全設施都癱瘓了？
britain's entire security apparatus has been taken down
而且你對此毫無頭緒？
and you know absolutely nothing?
那確實非常好地說明了說明了當前的情況 是的 夫人
That does pretty much sums up the situation, ma'am, yes.
好吧 那你最好趕緊找些能弄清真相的人！
Well, you better get someone on it and find me some answers!
是的 不過那正是問題所在 我們沒有可以調查的特工了
Yes, but that's the problem. We don't have any agents left.
他們都已經曝光了
They've all been outed.
所以找個老特工回來！
So bring back an old one!
所有小隊聽著 這裡是朱麗葉 原地等待目標出現
All units, this is Juliet echo. Stand by for target coordinates.
鎖定目標 重複 目標已鎖定
Target acquired. Repeat, target acquired.
好勒 看看我們抓到了誰？
Now then, what have we here?
抱歉 先生
Sorry, sir.
別在意 巴格利
Never mind, baggaley.
你的隱蔽和偽裝能力毫無疑問有了進步
Your concealment and camouflage work is definitely improving.
謝謝您 先生
Thank you, sir.
快來啊
Come on.
你也是 伊巴杜拉
You, too, ibadulla.
出色極了那是一流的大號陷阱洞
Excellent. That is a first-class man-trap.
獎勵 6點學院分！
Six house points. Yes!
好的 讓我們趕緊回學校吧 以免看守發現你們不在
Right, let's get back to school before matron notices you're missing.
還有別擔心 這裡已經沒別的陷阱了
And don't worry, there aren't any more booby traps.
當然這個是有點大
Apart from this one, of course.
英格力士老師？
Mr. English?
我們沒見到他 先生
We haven't seen him, sir.
好吧
Huh.
而這... 就是偽裝
And that's camouflage.
然後...出發！
And go!
接著是你
And go.
走你
您們孩子的安全是我們最重視的問題
The welfare of your children is our Paramount concern.
他們從不用直面任何不必要的風險
They're never exposed to any unnecessary risk,
我可以向您們保證
I assure you.
我覺得該給你的炸彈處理課給個F 哈特斯利
I think that's an "f" for your bomb disposal coursework, hattersley.
你今晚看上去特別地美麗動人
"You're looking particularly beautiful tonight."
You're looking particularly beautiful tonight.
叮！~
"Ching!"
Ching!
祝您半學期愉快 先生 - 多謝
- Have a good half-term, sir! - Thank you.
致 喬尼·英格力士
憨豆特工3
憨豆特工3 再度出擊！
你不會是真的在告訴我 我們就只有他了吧？
Are you seriously telling me this is all we've got?
他們中大多數人要麼已經去世
Most of them are either dead,
要麼正處於前列腺手術後恢復期
having hip operations or recovering from prostate surgery.
好吧
Okay.
在您們聽取任務簡報之前 我們需要你重新簽署這份官方保密協議
Before your briefing, we'll need you to re-sign the official secrets act.
謝謝
Thank you.
多謝
謝啦
Thank you.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
你們中任何紳士還記得這個嗎？
Any of you gentlemen remember this?
哦 萬寶龍爆破筆 好些年沒見過了...
Ooh, the Montblanc blaster. Haven't seen one of those for years.
拿掉筆帽 如果沒記錯的話 在20秒內將筆帽重新蓋上
Take the cap off and, if memory serves, you've 20 seconds to replace it
或是把它當做擊暈手榴彈引爆
or it detonates with the force of a stun grenade.
謝了
Thank you.
茶在左邊 先生們
Teas on the left, gentlemen.
咖啡在右邊
And coffees on the right.
棒極了
Excellent.
哦 可惡 我忘付賬了
Oh, damn it, I forgot my pills.
還是喝咖啡吧...
Coffee. Oh.
來 請讓我為你端
Here, let me help you with that.
茶嗎？
Tea?
哦 這杯似乎需要加上一點熱水
Ooh, this one just needs a little top-up of hot water.
失陪了 我馬上回來
I'll be right back.
哦...
Ohl
啊 早上好 抱歉讓你等了這麼久
ah, good morning. Sorry to keep you.
其他人到了嗎？
Are the others here?
呃...
Um...
哦
Oh.
他們... 他們犯困了...
They, um... they nodded off.
好吧
Right...
所以說你到底是誰？
And who are you exactly?
英格力士
English.
- 喬尼·英格力士
- 好吧
- Johnny English. - Well...
英格力士
"English..."
你將馬上動身出發
You'll leave immediately.
我的人會在路上 給你完整介紹這次任務的內容
My people will give you the full briefing en route.
對了 你有什麼需要的嗎？
Oh, is there anything you need?
是的 我需要鼻腔型神經噴霧毒劑 和一套四號外骨骼裝甲...
Yes, nerve gas nasal spray, a type-four exoskeleton...
你還是寫一份清單比較好
You should probably start a list.
還有一枚絞殺手錶 橡皮表帶 不要鋼表帶的款式
And a garroting watch, with a rubber strap, not the steel bracelet
因為鋼表鏈會卡住我手腕上的汗毛
because the links get caught in the little hairs on my wrist.
哦 我還需要一位鮑夫
Oh, and I'll also need a bough.
Bough也有樹枝的意思
什麼樹枝？
What's a bough?
長官！
Sir!
見到你真是太棒啦！
Wonderful to see you!
好啦好啦 鮑夫 咱們要去執行一個任務 不是去度蜜月
Yes, all right, bough. We're going on a mission, not a honeymoon.
哦 當然是的 長官
Yes, of course, sir.
我想應該是你皮帶上的扣針卡住了我的襯衫 長官？
I think it's the pin of your buckle, sir. It's caught on my jumper.
安啦 我看得出哪裡出了問題 鮑夫
Yes, I can see what's wrong, bough.
如果你往左邊動 我往右邊
If you go to your left and I'll go to my right.
抱歉 不對 如果你走你的右邊 我走我的左邊
I'm sorry, no, if you go to your right and I'll go to my left.
也不對 如果我順時針轉身 你逆時針轉
No. If I go clockwise and you go anti-clockwise...
呃 不 我覺得這好像更弄不開了 長官
Er, no, I think that's making it worse, sir.
唔... 我真意外這竟然不管用...
Hmm. I'm surprised that didn't work.
早安 先生 我準備好了您的特工通信裝備
Good morning, sir. I have your agent activation pack here.
內部生產的專用智能手機
Department-issue smartphone.
５８０萬像素４．７寸高清屏
580-megapixel camera, 4.7-inch retina hd display.
哼哼 挺巧妙 所以說它能發射出什麼？毒飛鏢？
Hmm-hmm. Ingenious. And what does it shoot? Poison darts?
它...不能發射任何東西 就是部手機
It doesn't shoot anything. It's a phone.
上面有 Twitter 和 Instagram
There's a Twitter handle, instagram feed
Uber 優步 海外的滴滴打車 始創於美國硅谷
以及支持安全登錄的 部門專用 Uber賬戶
and secure login for the department uber account.
他在搞什麼 鮑夫？
What's he on about, bough?
我需要一件武器 不是一連串的不實用的官腔廢話
I need a weapon. Not a box of gobbledygook.
我想... 呃，英格力士特工想嘗試說的重點是...
I think, uh, what agent English is getting at
長官 所有這些程序都是高度可追蹤的信息源
Sir, is all this is highly trackable.
因為我們面對的是一個非常複雜的數字目標...
But since we're dealing with a very sophisticated, digital target,
所以我們可能需要採取更低調、低科技的方法來避免被注意到
We might be less visible if we took a more analog, low-tech approach.
正是如此
Exactly.
我明白了
I see.
啊 那有什麼我可以幫你提供的嗎？
Ahh, Is there anything else I can get you?
一把槍
A gun.
我們...已經不再生產槍支了
We don't really do guns anymore.
只是 給他把槍
Just get him a gun.
好吧 槍槍
Right, a gun.
好吧 實際上第一次拿出這個
Right. Haven't actually done one of these before.
「根據健康和安全指示第14條 我有義務告知您——
"It is my obligation under section 14 of the health and safety directive to inform you
你將使用的設備可能會造成創傷和肢體傷害...」
"that the equipment with which you are about to be issued can cause injury and bodily harm.
「更多需要注意的是 任何對堅果過敏的特工都應該知道追蹤嫁棗油的痕跡...」
"Furthermore, any agents with nut allergies should be aware that traces of cashew oil..."
謝謝你
Thank you.
好吧 交通工具
Right, transport.
所以 選輛你想開的吧
So, take any hybrid you want.
就是她啦
I'll take this one.
哦 別開玩笑了 英格力士 這輛是古董紀念品
Oh, don't be ridiculous, English. This car is a relic.
喝汽油 漏燃油 連被動安全裝置都沒...
Drinks petrol, leaks oil and has no passive,
更別提主動安全了
let alone active safety features.
你知道這輛車還缺少什麼嗎 長官？
Do you know what else it doesn't have, sir?
它也沒搭載衛星導航和電腦芯片
Satellite navigation or a single computer chip.
這讓它在數字敵人面前完全隱形
Making it completely invisible to a digital enemy.
英格力士特工要求的裝備拿來了 長官
The equipment agent English requested, sir.
謝啦
Thank you.
- 手機鮑夫？
- 好的
- Phone, bough? - Yeah.
那高科技惡棍永遠看不到我們接近他...
That hi-tech villain of yours will never see us coming.
讓我們來看看都有什麼
Let's see what they've given us.
外骨骼裝備 爆炸棉簽 充氣式舊鞋盒
Exoskeleton, exploding cotton buds, the old shoebox inflatable.
嗯哼
Hmm.
- 哦這是什麼？
- 瞬間釋放超高能量的藥片
- Ooh, what are these? - Instant release super high energy pills.
未成年觀眾 注意這是電影 別做傻事
就像把手指插到電源插座裡 高度推薦
Like sticking your fingers in an electric socket. Highly recommended.
好吧 所以這紅色的一定是令人昏睡的強力安眠藥
Right, so, the red ones must be the total knockout sleeping pills.
對啦
Correct.
唔... 可能還是貼上標籤比較好
Hmm. Probably worth labeling these.
哦
Oh.
看啊 長官 還有小糖果
Look, sir. Sweeties.
哦嗚~
Ooh.
讓我嘗嘗
Hang on a minute.
我一直很喜愛這些果凍軟糖
I always did love a jelly baby.
我可不喜歡 鮑夫 果凍是凝膠炸藥的縮寫
I wouldn't if I was you, bough. "Jelly" is short for gelignite.
一小口就會轟掉你的頭
One bite and it'll take the top of your head off
連同這輛車的車頂一起
along with the roof of the car.
所以這些是用來做什麼的？
So, what does this do?
只是卷磁帶 鮑夫
It's a mixtape, bough.
- 所以目的地是？
- 法國南部長官
- So, destination? - South of France, sir.
那次網絡攻擊似乎是從一家旅館的Wi-Fi信號發出
That cyber attack seems to have been launched from the Wi-Fi signal of a hotel in antibes.
Initial D！
長官 我剛從總部收到一份傳真
Sir? Sir, I've just had a fax through from hq.
調查旅館裡所有使用Wi-Fi 的旅客背景身份
Background checks on all the guests that accessed the Wi-Fi network.
你瞧 誰需要用電子郵件？
You see? Who needs email?
呃...
Um...
有個名字被重點標記了 長官
One name has raised a red flag, sir.
塞巴斯蒂安·林奇 前陸軍軍事情報人員
Sebastian lynch, ex-army and military intelligence.
現在他服務於出價最高的買家
Now selling his services to the highest bidder.
- 我們到哪兒才能找到他？
- 就在你正前方長官
- Where do we find him? - Directly ahead, sir.
他預定過 科特迪羅餐廳八點的座位
He's got an 8:00 reservation at the cote de roc restaurant.
問題在於如何接近 進行全面監測 長官
The problem's going to be getting close enough for a full surveillance, sir.
不一定非要如此
Not necessarily.
計劃簡單 一共兩步 你分散注意力 我去拿手機
Simple plan, two parts. You provide the distraction, I'll get the phone.
- 好的長官
- 以及從現在開始
- Yes, sir. - And from now on,
或許我們該裝作法國服務員的口音
perhaps we should sound like French waiters.
法果腔？
French waiters?
似的
Yees.
上吧
Go on.
你現在忙完了嗎？
Are you finished now?
麵包圈？
Bread roll?
好的 多謝
Yes, thank you.
出色的選擇 女士
Excellent choice, madame.
晚上嚎
Good evening.
泥們孩好吧？
How are you?
要麵包圈嗎 先生？
Bread roll, sir?
好的 謝謝
Yes. Thank you.
再等一下
One second.
不好意思 能否麻煩？
Excuse me, would you mind?
哦 好滴 晚上嚎
Oh, yes. Evening.
月色真美
Evening.
蟹蟹
Thank you.
我手機呢？
Where's my phone?
在那兒呢
That is your phone.
哦嗚
Ooh.
謝謝
Thank you.
這位先生！
Monsieur.
那個... 能請你幫我去掉我妻子的龍蝦殼嗎？
The, uh, shell on my wife's lobster, could you remove it, please?
好滴
Yees.
呃... 恩姆...
Uh... um...
哼嗯...
Hmm.
讓我幫泥砸開吧
Let me crack it for you.
這是當年憨豆在法國餐廳 被吃掉那只龍蝦的復仇嗎www
噢！哦！
Ow! Oh!
噢嗚！
Owl
你好？
hello?
塞巴斯蒂安 別摻和
Sebastian, don't get involved.
哈
Ah.
噠噠~
Voila.
嗯... 祝您好胃口
Hmm. Bon appetit.
簡直完美 鮑夫~
Textbook, bough.
只是些假期照片 長官
Just holiday snaps, sir.
等一下 這照片
Wait a minute, this photo.
是敵人接入Wi-Fi 攻擊我們的那天 還有看
It was taken the same day our villain accessed the Wi-Fi, and look.
無論誰在那艘遊艇上
Whoever was on that yacht
都可以輕鬆地使用旅館Wi-Fi 發出那個信號 然後乘船離開
could easily have used the hotel's Wi-Fi, sent that signal and then just sailed away.
我想現在是我們付費參觀 Dot CALM號的時候了
I think it's time we paid the Dot CALM a visit.
運算程序
Algorithms.
我們的身邊無處不在
We are surrounded by them.
運算程序推動著我們的生活
Algorithms run our lives,
選擇電視節目 播放喜愛音樂 甚至幫我們找到一個約會
choose our TV shows, stream our music. Even find us a date.
我好像認識這傢伙 不是嗎？
I know this chap, don't I?
沒錯 他就是那個和卡戴珊約會的硅谷億萬富翁
Yes, he's that silicon valley billionaire who dated a Kardashian.
兩位卡戴珊姐妹 還有黑眼豆豆女主唱 閉嘴好好看
Two Kardashians and a black-eyed pea. Keep watching.
但讓我們假設有個針對於整個國家的運算程序
But supposing there was an algorithm for an entire country.
一個應用於每個人自身問題的運算程序
A single algorithm that could be applied to every one of its problems.
一個運算程序可以讓平庸國家變得——
A single algorithm that could take a second-rate nation and make it
世界一流
world class.
每個國家都數據氾濫
Every nation is awash with data.
所以現在 我們比任何時候都需要將這些數據 用於為人們服務
So now, more than ever, we need to put that data to work for the people.
這幾行代碼就能帶來那種改變
These few lines of code will deliver the kind of change
是他們長久以來 一生所夢想的
they have been dreaming of their entire lives.
我是 Xander 我熱愛數據
I am Xander. I love data.
他真他喵聰明
He's so clever.
他年輕 性感 他取得了非同凡響的成功！
He's young, he's sexy, he's insanely successful!
喬布斯：Excuse 喵？
這正是我需要人們與我 交流合作所需要的品質！
Just the qualities we need people to associate with me!
好吧 首相大人
Yes, prime minister.
人們會變成那樣 等他開始過來和我們一同工作時
And they will do when he starts working with us.
但為什麼硅谷的億萬富翁會和我們一起工作？
But why would a silicon valley billionaire work with us?
你只管把他安排進10號的日程 讓我來搞定他
Just get him into number 10 and let me work on him.
- 好的夫人
- 快去快去
- Yes, ma'am. - Go on.
哦 老天 又怎麼了？
Oh, god, now what?
又發生了另一次襲擊 首相大人
There's been another attack, prime minister.
- 又來！
- 空中交通管制
- Oh! - Air traffic control.
有人把前往歐洲的每場航班都改到盧頓了
Someone's rerouted every flight in Europe to luton.
看在上帝份兒上 告訴我你派到這個領域的特工 取得了一些進展！
For god's sake, tell me the agent you've got in the field is making some progress!
所以 我們怎麼才能找到那艘遊艇？長官
So, how are we gonna find the location of that yacht, sir?
很簡單 鮑夫 我們給 MI7打電話就行了
Very easily, bough. We ring MI7.
你好 你好？是的 我需要一艘船的位置 它叫——
Hello, hello? Yes, I need the location of a boat called...
你好？你好 是的 一艘叫 Dot CALM的船
Hello? Hello, yes. A boat called the Dot CALM.
對 是個雙關語沒錯
Yes, it's a play on words. Yeah.
哪裡？
Where?
看上去就在半公里外 長官
Looks about half a mile out, sir.
所以我們是游泳去還是...
Do we wanna try and swim it or...
不用 鮑夫 這裡該充氣鞋盒出場啦
No, bough. This is a job for the shoebox inflatable.
不 別在車裡打開它！長官！
No, don't open it in the car, sir!
你那邊能摸到門把手嗎？
Can you reach your door handle?
不能 長官
No, sir.
我試試我這邊
I'll try my side.
好的 鮑夫 我們的目標是在不被察覺的情況下登船
Right, bough, our aim is to get on board without anyone noticing.
所以具體怎麼做？
And how are we gonna do it?
- 磁力鞋出場
- 機智長官
- Magnetic boots. - Brilliant, sir.
用法簡單
Simple mechanism.
左開關激活左邊鞋子 右開關激活右邊的
Left switch activates left boot. Right switch activates right.
好的 行動吧
Okay, let's go.
記住 這次任務中最重要因素的是出其不意
Remember, the absolutely vital element of this mission is surprise.
除非你起得特別早 才可能勝過英國情報人員
Now, you have to get up pretty early in the morning to outwit British intelligence.
行動！
Quick!
晚上好 先生們
Good evening, gentlemen.
讓我們先從自我介紹開始吧？
Shall we start with your names?
顯然你並不清楚自己在和誰打交道
Clearly you have no idea who you're dealing with.
所以我才在問你的名字
That's why I'm starting with your names.
實際上 你能到下面來嗎？
Actually, would you mind coming down here?
這樣真的很難交流
It's really hard to have a conversation like this.
我有個更好的想法
I have a better idea.
情況不妙 這門堅若磐石 長官
It's no good, it won't move, sir.
我們會弄清楚的
We'll see about that.
低強度爆炸棉棒
Low-intensity exploding cotton bud.
會不會有點過於火爆了？這裡空間狹小 長官
That's quite a powerful charge for such a small space, sir.
哦 想太多
Oh, nonsense.
這聲音就像爆米花一樣輕微
There will just be a slight pop.
我們要不要去找貨艙 然後搜尋那個信號來源？
Shall we locate the hold and look for the source of that signal?
我覺得我們應該去找貨艙！然後搜尋那個信號來源！
I think we should locate the hold and look for the source of that signal!
走起！
Come on!
我覺得咱們找到那個惡棍了 鮑夫！
I'd say we have our villain, bough!
你需要小點聲 長官！
You need to keep your voice down, sir.
還有我們絕不會讓他溜走
And we're not going to lose him.
把果露泉給我
Hand me the sherbet fountain.
吸三下 位置發送器就會激活
Three sucks and the location transmitter is activated.
「杜松子酒店」將從3萬英尺的高空中 以充滿敵意的姿態出現
This gin palace will show up as a hostile from 30,000 feet.
哇哦
Hmm.
這下敵人就成了活靶子
This is now an enemy target.
麥麗素何在？
Aniseed balls.
如果你想殺我 那麼你已經動手了
If you'd wanted to kill me, you would have already done so.
後會有期
Till we meet again.
噢
Owl
好吧 這真是比我預期的還快
Well, that was sooner than I expected.
噢 噢 噢...
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
你覺得她是誰 長官？
Who do you think she is, sir?
這個嘛 如果她不是那艘船的主人
Well, if she's not the owner of that yacht,
那她一定知道那船是誰的
then she knows who is.
不論哪種 她是這次事件的關鍵
Either way, she's the key to this case.
在這次事件發生之前 你在教書嗎 長官？
Is it true you were teaching, sir? Before all this blew up?
如果「教書」你指的是...
If by "teaching" you mean
尋找有潛力的諜報人才 那麼是的 我在「教書」
scouting for potential intelligence operatives then yes, I was.
這樣
Hmm.
實際上 我已經結婚了 長官 不知你聽說了沒
I actually got married, sir. I don't know if you heard.
沒
No.
好吧
Hmm.
她叫 麗迪雅
Yeah, Lydia.
可愛的女孩
Lovely girl.
你從沒想過自己結婚的事嗎？長官
You never think about getting hitched yourself, sir?
已婚男人沒有生活可言 鮑夫 伴隨危險、持續不斷旅行的生活...
This is no life for a married man, bough. The danger, the constant travel.
給您 先生
Here you go, sir.
麗迪雅在我的生活中更重要 長官
More Lydia's life than mine, sir.
她在海軍
She's in the Navy, you see.
做什麼 是廚師嗎？
What, as a cook?
還是某種海航秘書或是什麼的？...
Or some kind of seagoing secretary or...
哦不 長官 她是核潛艇的長官
Oh, no, sir. She's the captain of a nuclear submarine.
哦 這樣啊
Oh, right. Hmm.
你覺得我們該給那輛紅色阿斯頓加點油嗎？
Do you think we should get some petrol for the Aston, sir?
安啦 阿斯頓馬丁意外地非常經濟 鮑夫
No. An Aston Martin is surprisingly economical, bough.
此外 看來我們有客人到了
Besides, it looks like we're in business.
動身吧
Come on.
看起來像是輛電動的車
Looks like an electric car, sir.
是啊 發動機聲音聽上去跟鼻毛修剪器一樣
Yes, and sounds like a nose hair trimmer.
一堆３Ａ電池不可能是經典款式的英國馬力對手！
A bunch of triple-a batteries is no match for old-fashioned British horsepower.
看看她的過彎 看上去很輕鬆不是嗎？長官
Look at her cornering. Seems so effortless, doesn't it, sir?
什麼？
The what?
我說導彈 鮑夫 那個搭載有催淚彈頭的
The missile, bough, the one with the tear gas warhead.
但他們只是自行車選手 長官 我們等一會兒就過去了
But they're just cyclists, sir. We'll get past in a minute.
他們是法國選手 鮑夫
They're French cyclists, bough,
還有他們妨礙了女王陛下的特工任務
and they're obstructing her majesty's secret service.
雨刷已武裝 長官
Wiper stalk is armed, sir.
抱歉
Sorry.
非常抱歉 深感歉意
Terribly sorry. We do apologize.
別說了 鮑夫 你應該鼓勵他們
Stop it, bough, you'll only encourage them.
- 我們現在怎麼辦長官？
- 耐心點鮑夫
- What are we gonna do now, sir? - Patience, bough.
開那麼快 她的電池隨時都會沒電
Driving like that, her battery will be dead any moment.
然後她就會尷尬地停下
And she'll roll to a humiliating stop.
鮑夫 保持車裡有油是你的工作
Bough, it is your job to keep an eye on the fuel Gauge.
真是令人驚艷的車技 請問閣下是...
Very impressive driving, Mr...
戈萊特利
Golightly.
巴茲爾·戈萊特利
Basil golightly.
你也表現得不錯 小姐貴姓...
And you're rather useful yourself, miss...
布魯托娃 奧菲利亞·布魯托娃
Bhuletova. Ophelia bhuletova.
哦
Hmm.
這位是...
And this is...
柯林
Colin.
我以為我們在用假名
I thought we were using fake names.
這就是假名
That is a fake name.
哦 好吧
Oh, right.
沒錯 這位是柯林
Yes, this is Colin,
所以我是...
and I'm...
「達茲爾」
"Dasil."
達茲爾
Dasil.
巴茲爾
Basil.
好吧 巴茲爾
Well, basil,
也許有個更簡單的方法處理這件事
Maybe there is a simpler way of doing this.
喝點酒 或許？
Over a drink perhaps?
那真是 樂意之極
Well, that would be lovely.
我們八點在濱海卡涅酒吧見好嗎？
Shall we say the bar at the hotel de Paris in cagnes-sur-mer? 8:00?
好極 一言為定
Mmm. It's a date.
好吧
Well,
我想我的「耗光燃油」策略很奏效
I think my "running out of fuel" ruse worked pretty well.
可不是嘛
Mmm.
又怎麼了？
What?
新人醫生 他們在罷工
Er, junior doctors. They've confirmed they are going on strike
地鐵司機也跑出來支持
and the tube drivers are coming out in support.
哦 天哪 反對派那些人 他們又死灰復燃了？
Oh, god. Leader of the opposition, has he come round from his heart surgery?
是的 首相大人
Yes, prime minister.
哦 上帝啊 什麼時候我才能輕鬆點！你又是什麼事？
Oh, Jesus Christ, when will something go right for me? What do you want?
他們又攻擊我們了 首相大人
They've hit us again, prime minister.
- 什麼？
- 入侵了中央交通控制系統
- Huh? - Hacked into the central traffic control system.
沒錯 他們把倫敦的交通信號燈都變成了紅色
Yes, they've turned every traffic light in London to red.
我那該死的飲料在哪兒？
Where's my bloody drink?
你是在開玩笑吧？伏特加通寧 不加冰 不加通寧水
You've got to be joking? Vodka tonic, no ice, no tonic.
- 好的馬上來
- 哦沃爾塔先生已經到了夫人
- Yes, ma'am. - Oh, and Mr. Volta has arrived, ma'am.
沃爾塔先生 歡迎來到唐寧街
Mr. volta, welcome to downing street.
我讀過許多關於這幢美妙建築的書籍
I have read so much about this wonderful building.
這是威廉·肯特設計的三級樓梯嗎？
Is this the stone triple staircase designed by William Kent?
呃 沒錯 也許是 我並不確定
Um, yes, it probably is. I can't swear to it.
- 我們是否可以拍張．．．
- 圖像正在處理
- Can we do a quick... - Needs Photoshop.
哦！那還真是... 呃 這邊請
Oh! This way. hmm... this way.
我來的有些晚 非常抱歉
I am horribly late, I do apologize.
交通問題 這是我不喜歡倫敦的地方
It's the traffic, it's the one thing I don't love about London.
是的 沒錯 我必須承認我們在燈光方面有點小問題 不是很嚴重
Yes, well, I must admit we are having a slight problem with the lights at the moment. Nothing major.
如果你想 我可以看看能否解決？這有點像我所在的行業領域
If you wanted, I could take a look? It is kind of what I do.
我認為這實際上要比你所在的領域更複雜...
I think it's actually a little bit more complex than...
Xander 找個倫敦交通控制中心的網址
Xander, get a web address for London's traffic control center.
這是登錄頁面 傑森 你持有密碼嗎？
Here is the login page, Jason. Do you have a password?
呃...
Um...
- 我不會透露如果你也睜一隻眼閉一隻眼
- 好吧
- I won't tell if you won't. - Right you are.
正在繞過安全檢測 安全檢測已跳過
Bypassing security. Security bypassed.
哦 技術大佬
Oh, that's terrific.
- 有人正在攻擊你們
- 哦我不那麼認為
- Someone is hacking you. - Oh, I don't think so.
DoS攻擊 沒錯 原始但絕對有效
Denied service attack. Yeah, primitive but effective.
你知道其實我們可以嘗試 重新分配服務請求到我們在內華達州的服務器農場
You know what we could try, rerouting all service requests to our server farm in Nevada.
- 呃
- 我．．
- Um... - I.
重新分配 傑森
Rerouting, Jason.
重分配 完成
Rerouting complete.
給力！
Crikey.
所以 你想和我談的是什麼？
So, what was it you wanted to talk to me about?
你 傑森
You, Jason.
出去
Get out.
我想談談你
I want to talk about you.
出色極了 鮑夫 馬上就到
Excellent, bough. Nearly there.
就差一點
Nearly there.
這真是家不錯的酒店 鮑夫
This is actually a really nice hotel, bough.
我要朝右轉了
I'm turning to the right.
我們一個人拖住布魯托娃小姐 另一個人搜索她的房間好嗎 長官？
Shall one of us keep miss bhuletova busy while the other searches her room, sir?
好主意 如果你發現了什麼警告我
Good idea, bough. Alert me if you find anything.
戈萊特利先生
Mr. golightly.
哦...
Oh...
就是我
Indeed.
我還以為你大概不會來
I thought perhaps you weren't coming.
恰恰相反 野馬也攔不住我
On the contrary, wild horses couldn't keep me away.
女士 先生
Madame? Monsieur?
晚上好 你想來杯什麼？
Evening. What would you like?
我今晚有點思鄉 就來杯莫斯科旅子吧
I'm feeling a little homesick tonight. I'll have a Moscow mule.
那我就來杯倫敦...
And I'll have a London...
旅鼠吧 多謝
Lemming, please.
我不確定 你點的是？
I'm not sure, what...
就是 呃... 杜松子、伏特加、達馬尼亞克、雪莉...
It's, uh, gin, vodka, darmagnac, sherry,
我就靜靜地看你裝... O x O
加上一點帕爾馬乾酪...
with just a little bit of parmesan.
所以 什麼讓你來到了法國南部？
So, what brings you to the south of France, miss...
比利...波利...
Bhilli... bholly...
布魯托娃
Bhuletova.
我只是拜訪一個朋友
I'm just visiting a friend of mine.
哦~
Hmm.
這位朋友是 Dot CALM號遊艇的主人嗎？
And would this friend be the owner of the Dot CALM?
哼
Hmm.
沒錯 他是的
Yes, he would.
那麼你呢？
And what about you,
巴茲爾
basil?
哦 我只是因為生意上的事到這兒
Oh, I'm just here on business.
不過 它很快就變成了一種樂趣
Although, it's rapidly turning into pleasure.
哦！我喜愛這些小零食
Ooh! I love these.
它們真的很辣
They're really hot.
你還好嗎？
Are you all right?
嗯吶 還行
Yes, fine.
哼
Hmm.
乾杯
Cheers.
我不確定我以前有沒有遇到過像你這樣的男人 巴茲爾
I'm not sure I've ever met a man quite like you, basil.
讓我明確告訴你吧
Let me clear up the uncertainty for you.
你從未
You haven't.
抱歉 巴茲爾 我明天還要早起
I'm sorry, basil. I have to get up really early tomorrow morning.
哦 那可真可惜
Oh, that's a shame.
情況如何 長官？
How did you get on, sir?
哦 天啊 多麼美妙的一位女性 美妙極了
Oh, gosh, what a wonderful woman, bough. Wonderful.
好好
Right.
迷人 知性美
Charming. Intelligent.
可愛的幽默感 很明顯是完全無辜的
Lovely sense of humor. And obviously entirely innocent.
儘管如此 我闖入她的房間發現了三本護照 長官
Although, I broke into her room and she does have three passports, sir.
羅馬尼亞人 保加利亞人 俄國人 每本上面都是不同名字
Romanian, Bulgarian, Russian. Different name in each.
所以她嫁過三次不同的人
So she's been married to three different people.
在她這個年紀可不常見 鮑夫
Not unusual in this day and age, bough.
除此之外 我還發現了一些絞線和兩盒炸藥
And I also found some garroting wire and two boxes of ammunition.
好吧 一個女人 單身旅行 不能不沒點防備
Well, single woman, traveling alone, you can't be too careful.
你不覺得她可能是個特工 長官？
You don't think she might be a spy, sir?
特工？
A spy?
我想我知道特工長什麼樣 鮑夫
I think I know what a spy looks like, bough.
唉
Oh.
長官？
Sir?
長官！
Sir!
我剛和倫敦打過電話
I just got off the phone to pin London.
那艘船主人的身份查明了
He's found out who the owner of that yacht is.
傑森·沃爾塔！
Jason volta!
這世界上最有權勢的互聯網億萬富翁 長官
The world's most powerful Internet billionaire, sir!
並且他現在就在倫敦
And he's in London, right now.
首相正在親自和他談判一項貿易協議
The prime minister is personally negotiating a trade deal with him.
好吧 那我們該出發了
Well, what are we waiting for?
你不覺得我們可以稍微慢一點嗎 長官？
Do you think we might slow down a little, sir?
什麼？
What?
沒什麼！
Never mind!
隨著又一次網絡攻擊 首相面臨的壓力也越來越大
- 英格蘭的每輛火車？
- 是的長官
- Every train in england? - Yes, sir.
它們都想停在 布里斯托爾寺院草原站
They're all trying to terminate at Bristol temple meads.
早安 長官！
Morning, sir!
- 你看這個了嗎英格力士？
- 看了
- You see this, English? - Yes!
請坐
Please.
哦！
Ooh!
告訴我你們都發現了什麼？我好告知首相大人
Tell me you've got something I can take to the prime minister.
對這一切該負責的人的名字嗎？長官
Would the name of the man responsible do, sir?
出色至極 英格力士 說吧
Excellent, English, yes.
他是 傑森...
It's Jason...
沃爾塔 長官 是傑森·沃爾塔
Volta, sir. Jason volta.
什麼？
What?
你在問罪穿著閃亮鎧甲的午夜騎士？
You're accusing the pm's knight in shining armor?
我需要強有力的證據！
I'd need hard evidence!
那會是...
Which...
所以英格力士特工建議 對沃爾塔在薩里郡的鄉村別墅進行滲透
Is why agent English is proposing a penetration of volta's country estate in surrey.
對 對 對...
Yes, yes, yes, yes...
好吧 做你需要做的 英格力士
Well, do what you have to do, English.
但看在上帝份上！一定要謹慎行動
But for god's sake! be discreet about it.
哦...
Oh! Oh.
醒了
Good.
明白
Oh. Oh.
虛擬現實？
"Virtual reality"?
是的 先生
That's right, sir.
P 建立了沃爾塔別墅內部的計算機模型
P's built a computer model of the inside of volta's mansion.
當您戴上這個頭部設備 會讓您視聽感官上像是到了別墅裡面一樣
When you put on this headset, it will look and feel as if you are inside the house.
您可以開關門 上下樓梯
You'll be able to open and close doors, walk up and down staircases,
完整地去熟悉適應它的建築佈局
completely familiarize yourself with its layout.
這塊板可以向任何方向移動 所以你可以走動...
This floor moves in any direction. So you can walk...
在虛擬世界裡走多遠都不用離開這個房間
You can walk as far as you want in the virtual world without ever actually leaving this room.
唯一要注意的是 長官
One thing though, sir.
這種體驗可能會讓你迷失方向
The experience can be very disorientating.
這是完全的沉浸式體驗
It's completely immersive
有些人會完全忘記 自己實際身處的環境
and some people lose all track of their actual surroundings.
我想我們可以非常確定這種情況不會發生
I think we can pretty much guarantee that's not gonna happen.
我需要您在 健康和安全聲明上簽字確認
I'll just need you to sign the health and safety releases.
請允許我去找一台 iPad
Would you excuse me while I find an iPad.
哦 陪他去吧 鮑夫 如果我們不催著點他 一整天都會耗在這兒
Oh, go with him, bough. If we don't chivvy him along we'll be here all day.
哼..
Hmm.
啊~
Ah.
看著點路！
Watch out!
目標
搞什麼！？
正在關門
下樓中...
你好 今天怎麼樣？
嘿！
Hey!
抱歉 先生 但我想恐怕您得離開了
I'm sorry, sir, but you're going to have to leave.
噢！
Ow!
三小！？
What the...
噢！
Ow!!
所以我們馬上就要抵達海軍部大樓了
So, we'll shortly be arriving at admiralty house.
以及 那實際上曾是 奧利弗·克倫威爾自己的房子
And, er, that actually used to be Oliver cromwell's own house. Um...
呃...
Uh...
然後我們將去參加皇家騎兵衛隊的遊行
And then we'll be going to horse guards parade.
也許你想坐下 這位先生？
Perhaps you'd like to sit down, sir?
儘管如此 我相信我們這次任務的特工正在取得重大進展
However, the agent we have on this mission is confident he's making major progress.
以及 呃 是的 我們找到了一個潛在嫌疑犯 已經被確認
And, uh, yes, we have a potential suspect, he's been identified.
進一步的調查正在秘密進行之中...
And further covert investigations are now ongoing.
沒錯 都冷靜點
Yes, quite.
所以我期待這方面有更多消息能宣佈
So I expect to have more to announce on this front
在短期內...
shortly.
長官？
Sir?
嗯？
Mmm?
- 一切都還正常吧長官
- 是的我已經完成了鮑夫
- Is everything all right, sir? - Yes, I've done it, bough.
小孩子過家家 不知有什麼可大驚小怪的
Child's play. Don't know what all the fuss was about.
很高興再次會面 首相大人
Pleasure to see you again, prime minister.
這是全息影像的會話 很常見 您只是普通點交流就好
It's a hologram. Apparently you just speak to it normally.
這是我的榮幸
The pleasure's all mine.
不想催促你  但有什麼是你特別需要的嗎？
Hate to rush you, but was there something in particular you needed?
實際上 我只是來電想問下你是否有認真考慮下
Actually, I was just calling really to see if you had had a chance to think things over.
我有
I have.
但問題是 菲奧娜 我實際上並不關心人們的安全問題
But the thing is, Fiona, I just don't really do other people's security.
不是我不在乎 而是你的基礎設施很陳舊
Not that I don't want to. But your infrastructure is old.
此外 唯一能保持你安全的方法就是將你的數據儲蓄在我個人的服務器上
Plus the only way I could keep you secure in the meantime would be by storing all your data on my own servers.
- 很顯然那是．．．
- 可以傑森！
- Obviously, that would be... - Yes. Jason,
我真正想做的是在G12峰會上宣佈這次合作
What I really want to do is announce this tie-up at the G12 meeting.
我們達成共識了嗎？
Do we have a deal?
祝你好運 長官
Good luck, sir.
嘿
Hey.
怎麼了 老闆？
Sir?
我說過在那裡準備好直升機
I said to get the chopper ready. Right there.
老闆 馬上去辦
Sir. Right away, sir.
「多謝」你
Thank you.
- 泰勒在嗎
- 在
- Tyler, come in. - Copy.
泰勒 你能現在準備一台直升機嗎？
Tyler, can you prepare the chopper now?
我們總是這樣不期而遇 戈萊特利先生
We can't keep meeting like this, Mr. golightly.
好吧 的確
Oh, yes.
還是你打算不再說謊 告訴我你的真實姓名？
Or do you want to end this charade and tell me your real name?
走
Go.
你對自己所涉入的這個世界 有太多不知道的事了
There's so much you don't understand about this world you've got caught up in.
別再瞎扯了 你是英國特勤局的人
Spare me the idiot act. You're British secret service.
順便一提 你在法國的表現令人印象深刻 什麼時候發現我是特工的？
Impressive work in France, by the way. When did you realize I was a spy, too?
哦 差不多一見面就看穿了
Oh, pretty much straight away.
這樣...
Hmm.
我花了兩年時間臥底 本來任務簡單 直到你出現
I've spent two years undercover. Simple operation until you showed up.
不過我喜歡將事情簡單化
And I like to keep things simple.
簡單是我的中間名
"Simple" is my middle name.
看來你需要做個選擇了
It would seem you've got a choice to make.
- 暫停立場上的敵對關係？
- 成為短期搭檔？
- Temporary suspension of hostilities?  - A short-term partnership?
同意
- Agreed. - Hmm.
政治家比風投資本家更容易上當
Politicians are even more gullible than venture capitalists.
說的沒錯
That is correct.
給我一份目標名單的拷貝
Get me a copy of the target list.
保險起見 我們再對他們發起一次攻擊
We'll hit them once more just to be on the safe side.
- 把你的手機借我
- 你沒有手機？
- Give me your phone. - You don't have a phone?
一台手機可以告訴任何人你的精準位置
A phone will give anyone your precise location.
但它們對聯繫他人很有用
And yet they're so useful for making phone calls.
出色的見解 不過我並不打算打電話給任何人
Excellent. I'm not phoning anyone.
我要用它收集證據
I'm gathering evidence.
這是目標列表 傑森 四個標誌性的倫敦坐標
The target list, Jason. Four iconic central London landmarks.
- 請選擇一個
- 三號
- Make your selection. - Number three.
倫敦眼 摩天輪
The London eye.
這次網絡攻擊潛在可能影響到1萬6千名遊客
This cyber attack could potentially impact 16,000 visitors.
我發現他在樓梯那邊偷窺
I found him snooping around upstairs.
所以你是誰？
And who are you exactly?
我不會告訴你任何信息
I'm not telling you anything.
好吧
Hmm.
臉部識別軟體已啟動
Face recognition software launched.
喬尼·英格力士是林肯郡的一名地理老師
Johnny English is a geography teacher from lincolnshire.
更願意全副武裝地來上一堂歐洲資本課 英格力士先生
Rather heavily armed for a lesson on European capitals, Mr. English.
有什麼想法嗎 親愛的？
Any thoughts, sweetheart?
他是英國特工
He's British intelligence.
我們想法一樣 他所在的機構真是虛有其名
And there you have I, two words that have no right being in the same sentence together.
你真的認為我是孤身一人來這裡的？
Do you really think I came here alone?
我有一整只突擊隊在外面守候 時刻準備突擊進這裡
I have a team of crack operatives out there, right now, just waiting to strike.
好吧
Uh-huh.
長官！
Sir!
這國家到底發生什麼了！？
What has happened to this country?
這在一個世紀前是絕對不可能的
How is it possible that less than a century ago
那時的大英帝國統治著四分之一世界 現在卻依靠著某一個人
the British empire ruled a quarter of the globe and now it's relying on someone
像是你這種？
Like you?
嘿 站住！
Hey! Stop!
誰去攔住他？
Stop him?
行動
Go.
- 把門關上
- 遵命老闆
- Close the gates. - Yes, sir.
救命 停下！
Help! Stop!
前方有障礙 特蘭特納太太
Obstacle directly ahead, Mrs. trattner.
檢查你的後視鏡然後停車
Check your mirrors and bring the car to a stop.
不好意思 嘿！
Er, excuse me. Hey.
多謝
Thank you.
飆車吧！
Drive!
不好意思
Excuse me.
你...你知道自己在做什麼嗎？
What... what do you think you're doing?
不好意思 你不是個持證的教練
Excuse me! You are not a qualified instructor.
- 我的教練怎麼辦？
- 左轉
- But what about my instructor? - Turn left.
右轉
Turn right.
為了以後參考 我坐你的左邊
For future reference, I'm on your left.
請停下 別踩油門了 我沒法再開了！
Please, stop. I can't do this anymore!
我現在什麼都看不清了！
I can't see anything now!
好極
Good.
當我說「轉」的時候 迅速往右邊轉彎
When I say "go," turn sharp right.
好
Uh-huh.
三、二、一
Three, two, one.
轉！
Gol
回正、回正、回正...
and straighten up, straighten up, straighten up.
接著開！
And go!
動起來 追上去！
Let's go, let's go.
哦 這應該勉強過得去
Oh, now just bear left a little. Good.
開直點 開直點
Straighten up, straighten up.
贊啊！
Good!
說真的 剛才開的不錯 特蘭特納太太
Well, that was very good, Mrs. trattner.
我覺得你今天真的進步了許多
I think you made some real progress today.
你沒在聽我說什麼 英格力士
You're not hearing me, English.
鑒於首相和沃爾塔的新友誼 目前情況已經變了
Given the prime minister's new friendship with volta, the situation has changed.
但事實並非如此 這場襲擊是沃爾塔發起的
But the facts haven't, sir. That attack is volta's responsibility.
只是根據你的個人判斷 而不是其他任何人的
According to you, but not according to anyone else.
他在這裡嗎？
Is he here yet?
下午好 首相大人 所以他就是 呃...
Good afternoon, prime minister. So, this is, uh...
英格力士 首相大人 喬尼·英格力士
English, prime minister. Johnny English.
你有什麼需要明確說明的嗎？
What exactly do you have to say for yourself?
實際上還不少呢
Rather a lot, actually.
總而言之 像我這樣的人不會口腹蜜劍 首相大人
However, men like me don't deal in prevarication, prime minister,
所以讓我們直接切入重點吧
So let me get straight to the point.
傑森·沃爾塔就是這一連串襲擊背後的始作俑者
Jason volta is the man behind these attacks.
同時我還有強力證據證明
And I have the evidence to prove it.
我在沃爾塔的犯罪老巢記錄下了這些罪證
I managed to record this inside volta's country lair.
但我需要警告您 首相大人
But I should warn you, prime minister,
你所要見到的將是邪惡的化身
that what you're about to see is evil incarnate.
好吧
Hmm.
現在我們在 菲菲的三歲生日聚會！
Here we are at Fifi's third birthday!
真是令人興奮的一天！
And it's a very exciting day!
吐舌 萬歲 吐舌 萬歲！
Hip hip, hooray! Hip hip, hooray!
祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday to you
happy birthday to you
謝了
Thank you.
我能否問一下 你到底有什麼毛病？
Can I just ask, what is wrong with you?
國家正處於完全混亂的狀態
The country is in a state of complete chaos.
新聞界煽風點火 唯一一個能拯救我們的人 你卻指控他叛國罪
The press is wetting itself, and the only person capable of saving us is the man you're accusing of high treason.
他發出襲擊命令時 我就在那個房間 首相大人
I was in the room myself when he gave the order, prime minister!
但這這...
But there was a...
你知道我在房間裡做什麼嗎？英格力士
Do you know what I was in the room with, English?
讀你的文件 全部都看了一遍 所以我有幾個問題
Your file, which I've read, in its entirety, and I have a few questions.
你是不是把科特迪羅餐廳燒成灰燼？
Did you or did you not burn the cote de roc restaurant in antibes to the ground?
呃...
Um...
還有你是否向法國自行車選手發射了催淚飛彈？
And did you or did you not fire a guided missile at a peloton of French cyclists?
這個嘛...
Well...
你有沒跑到巴士車頂將導遊扔下車？
Before commandeering an open-top bus and tossing the tour guide off the top deck
然後跑到麵包店襲擊一位坐著輪椅的８２歲老婦人？
and then assaulting an 82-year-old grandmother in a sandwich shop
還用兩條法棍麵包瘋狂抽打了麵包店員工？
before battering the employee of said sandwich shop with two organic sourdough baguettes?
呃 我不記得有...
Uh, I don't remember the...
你知道這一切讓我有多困擾嗎？
Do you have any idea how hard it is to be me?
- 呃．．．
- 不知？
- Uh... - Hmm?
面對事件、真相和選民 還有那股被稱之為「國家媒體」的海嘯
Do you have even the foggiest notion of how virtually impossible it is to get anything done
在這些事面前 你難道連最基本「不能做的事」的模糊概念都沒有嗎！？
in the face of events and facts and voters and that Tsunami of tosspots we call "the national press"?
好不容易 我能為我的國家做些好事 然後發生什麼了？
Finally I get the chance to do something good for my country, and what happens?
宇宙把我送到你面前
The universe sends me you.
好吧 你知道我會說什麼嗎？
Well, do you know what I say?
我會說 去他喵的宇宙！!
I say, up the universe's arse!!
當然還有這句—— 你被開除了！
And do you know what else I say? You're fired.
川普：Give Me A High-Five~
此刻起立刻生效 現在給老娘我滾！
With immediate effect. Now get out!
還有確保我以後再也不會見到這個傻瓜 永遠的！
And make sure I never clap eyes on that imbecile ever again!
你要去哪裡 長官？
What are you doing, sir?
你覺得我能去哪兒？回家唄
What do you think I'm doing, bough? I'm going home.
但首相正在完成她和沃爾塔的交易
But the prime minister is finalizing her deal with volta.
她說要帶上他作為特邀嘉賓參加G12峰會
She's taking him to the G12 summit in Scotland as her special guest.
一切都結束了 鮑夫 我們對這一切根本無能為力
It's over, bough. And there's absolutely nothing we can do about it.
但 長官 我有個計劃
But, sir, I have a plan.
記得我妻子嗎？
Remember my wife?
收起你的擋板！
Clear your baffles!
- 穿山甲說什麼？
- 主意頭頂長官
- What? - Mind your head, sir.
噢！
Owl!
這表上說我們正在下沉
this says we're sinking.
她是有點老舊了 但她可以獻上一場地獄般的煙火表演
She's old and a little rusty, but she can put on a hell of a fireworks display.
G12政界峰會 加洛什城堡
出色的表現 指揮官
Excellent work, commander.
傑里米對您評價一直很高 英格力士特工
Jeremy has always spoken very highly of you, agent English.
誰？
Who?
哦
Oh.
哦 是的 沒錯
Oh, yes, yes.
我一直不太喜歡那些文職人員 所以
I'm no fan of the pen pushers myself, so
當命令為了首腦峰會時把我們派駐到這裡時
When orders came through stationing us here for the summit,
我想 那至少我也能知道地點在哪兒
Well, I thought a lift was the least I could do.
好極 讓我們動身出發吧 鮑夫
Right, let's get a move on, bough.
對了 你們應該不介意把手機一直關機吧 直到你們安全後再開
Oh, if you wouldn't mind keeping your mobiles off until you're well clear, gentlemen.
這裡的導彈發射系統有點像80年代的
The launch systems on the missiles are a bit 1980s.
對微波輻射有點敏感
Gets a tad twitchy around microwave radiation.
沒問題 指揮官 我們會用舊式經典風格來完成這次任務
No problem there, commander. We're doing this mission old-school.
這個地點完美極了
This spot is perfect.
來吧
Come on.
抱歉 長官
Sorry, sir.
快過來 隱蔽起來...
Come on, come on...
好了 鮑夫 我們的任務很簡單
Right, bough. Our mission here is simple.
機智地潛入沃爾塔的房間 帶走他
Gain access to volta's bedroom and take him out.
你打算怎麼進到那裡面？長官
How are you going to get up there, though, sir?
輕鬆至極 只要你有外骨骼裝甲
A walk in the park for the exoskeleton.
可以遠程操縱的 氯丁橡膠緊身衣
Remotely operated neoprene bodysuit.
增強穿戴者100倍的力量
Increases the wearer's strength 100 times.
好了 啟動它 把軟盤插進去然後出發
Right, power it up. Stick in the floppy disk and let's go.
稍等下...
Just...
天吶 長官
Crikey, sir!
武器什麼時候能準備好？
When will the weapon be ready?
只要首相今晚一簽署協議
As soon as the prime minister signs the agreement, tonight.
我該如何發射？
How do I fire it?
按一次攻擊就會觸發
Press once and the attack is launched.
隨後 每個參加 G12峰會國家的數據都將傳送到 Dot CALM號上的服務器裡
After which, the data of every G12 country will be transferred to the servers onboard the Dot CALM.
完美
Perfect.
啊
Ah.
乾杯
Cheers.
你一開始就為俄國情報部門工作
You're working for Russian intelligence and you have been from the start.
這就是我為什麼有你戒指裡毒藥的解藥
Which is why I've taken an antidote to the poison you keep in your ring,
就是你下到這杯飲料裡的毒藥
and which you've poured into this drink.
還取掉了你拿把槍裡的擊針
And removed the firing pin from that pistol.
每個人都得 為了自己的人生努力生活
Everyone has to make a life for themselves.
而你的令人悲傷 因為馬上就要...
It's just sad that yours is
結束
over.
哼嗯...
Hmm.
剛從我的3D打印機裡做好 100%的純塑料製成
Fresh from my 3D printer. Hundred percent plastic.
並且 100%致命
And 100% deadly.
殺掉我並不能救你
Killing me won't save you.
別那麼肯定
Don't bet on it.
講真？這不可能發生
Seriously, this cannot be happening.
哦 但這確實發生了
Oh, but it is.
扔掉槍
Drop the gun.
雙手舉到空中
Get your hands in the air.
你也是
And you.
沒時間搞這套 喬尼！
There's no time for this, Johnny!
哦 這不可能吧
Oh, it isn't possible.
你不可能和這個英格力士蠢蛋合作
You cannot be working with this English idiot!
把你的白日夢話 留到監獄裡念叨吧 沃爾塔
Save the pillow talk for your prison cell, volta.
- 你到裡面了嗎長官？
- 是的沒錯小鮑你可以把電源關了
- Are you inside, sir? - Yes, yes, bough, you can power down.
一切盡在我的控制之中...
Everything is under control.
好吧 你說關就關唄
Shut down.
現在我們更難進去了 長官
How do we get in now, sir?
有什麼妙招？
What's the plan?
嘿 你！
Hey, you!
站住！
Hey!
非常感謝你們 我希望你們得到了需要的一切
Thank you very much. I hope you have everything you need.
噢...
Owl!
我代表著整個英國
On behalf of the United Kingdom,
請允許我歡迎你來到這個古老的會議廳
May I welcome you here today to this ancient meeting chamber
偉大的蘇格蘭民族 他們曾解決諸多紛爭 建立了新聯盟
Where the great Scottish clans once settled their differences and forged new alliances.
一個我為了發佈特別信息 而精心挑選出的場所
A place I have specifically chosen in order to make a very special announcement.
長官？
Sir?
- 你還好吧長官？
- 不我一點也不好扶我起來鮑夫
- Are you all right, sir? - No, I'm not all right. Get me up, bough.
- 這可真重啊長官
- 我知道這有多重鮑夫
- It's very heavy, sir. - I know how heavy it is, bough.
我們必須趕到會場...
We've got to get to the conference...
搶先到那裡 避免沃爾塔...
To the conference room before volta...
避免沃爾塔啟動武器...
Before volta triggers his weapon.
所以 隨著我在這份協議上簽名...
And so, with my signature on this agreement...
這給了我無比的喜悅 哦...
It gives me great pleasure, oh,
向你們介紹 我的嘉賓及朋友 傑森·沃爾塔
to welcome to you, my guest, my friend, Jason volta.
隨時準備發動攻擊 傑森
Standing by to launch attack, Jason.
- 見鬼把我弄出這身破玩意兒
- 喬尼？
- Damn it, get me out of this stuff. - Johnny?
我看不見結合處 長官 這是扣環式的
I can't see the join, sir. It's the clasp.
鬆開扣環 這樣上下就分開了
Release the clasp and the top and the bottom separate.
一定是在你倒下時卡住了 長官
Must have jammed when you fell over, sir.
- 這種危急時刻鏈子不掉
- 等下試試這個
- For goodness sake. - Wait. Try this.
這真是...噴了不少油啊 長官
That is quite a lot of oil, sir.
哦 快點！快點 快點！...
Oh, come on! Come on, come on...
你們能否想像如果蘋果公司接管運行這個世界？
Can you imagine what the world would look like if it was run by apple?
又或者 谷歌，又或者...
Or Google? Or...
我？
Me?
你們認為還會存在失敗的學校嗎？
Do you think you'd have failing schools?
還會存在醫院裡無止境的等待？
Do you think you'd have endless waiting in your hospitals?
不
No.
覺得你們的機場還會有超長的排隊嗎？
Think you'd have such long lines in your airports?
- 不
- 並不會
- No. - No.
沒錯 不會發生的原因源於所有這一切 其實都是簡單的數據管理問題
No, because all of these are simple data management problems.
最終人們會像我一樣 共同熱愛數據！
And people like me, We love data!
我們生活在數據中...
We live for data.
哈！我...
Ha! My...
你知道我為了什麼而活嗎？沃爾塔
Do you know what I live for, volta?
上帝啊...
God.
消除你這樣滿嘴謊言 危害國家安全的惡棍！
Eliminating the threat that lying villains like you pose to this country!
唉 額滴神啊
Oh, for god's sake.
他是誰？
Who is he?
逮捕這個重傢伙
Arrest this whack job.
這裡唯一能下逮捕命令的人就是我
The only person ordering an arrest around here will be me.
沒必要擔心 女士們 先生們
There's no cause for concern, ladies and gentlemen,
你們現在在 女王陛下特勤局的可靠掌控局勢之下
You are now in the capable hands of her majesty's secret service.
而你 我的朋友 正在經歷一場不愉快的旅行
And you, my friend, are in for an uncomfortable ride.
噢嗚~~~
Owww Ooh...
我說到哪兒了來著？
Where was I?
生活在數據流中
Living for data.
正是如此
Exactly.
我的運算程序可以解決你們中每一個人的問題 只要我還有一樣東西——
My algorithms can solve every one of your problems as long as I have one thing.
控制權
Control.
那也正是你們現在要給我的
And that is what you are about to give me now.
傑森 我好奇你是否能澄清一下...
Jason, I wonder if you could just clarify...
閉嘴
Shut up.
嘿 你小子給我等下
Now, hold on.
城堡現在已封鎖
Castle now locked down
一切盡在你的掌控之下 傑森
and under your control, Jason.
這個無知的人剛才簽下的協議
The agreement this ignoramus just signed
不只給予我訪問英國所有數據的權限
didn't just give me access to all the UK's data.
還允許我接入北艾爾郡的一個接線盒
It also gave me access to a junction box, in north ayrshire
它連接著整個全球互聯網
that connects the entire world wide web.
禁用那個盒子裡的光纖電纜 互聯網將會不復存在
Disable the fiber-optic cables in that box and the Internet will cease to exist.
喬尼？你還好嗎？
Johnny? Are you okay?
你帶手機了嗎？我們需要呼叫外援
Have you got a phone? We need to call for backup.
現在沒時間搬救兵了 我要直接去找沃爾塔
There's no time for backup. I'm going after volta.
別把這部也搞丟！
And don't lose that one!
你們能明白全球互聯網關閉的後果嗎？
Do you understand what it means if I turn the Internet off?
城市將黯淡無光 飛機會從天空墜落
Cities will go dark. Planes will fall out of the sky.
列車會相撞 法律和秩序也將奔潰
Trains will collide. Law and order will break down
最後你們所熟悉的世界將會徹底結束
and the world as you know it will be over.
壓軸節目 別劇透 對吧？
Show, don't tell, right?
開始發起攻擊 傑森
Initiating attack, Jason.
取得接線盒控制權限
Taking control of junction box.
暫停英國和歐洲的互聯網及供電
Suspending Internet and electricity supply across britain and Europe.
攻擊階段一 完成
Stage one of attack complete.
女士們 先生們 我隨時可以停止攻擊
Ladies and gentlemen. I can stop the attack
只要你們每個人都在協議上面簽名授權
as long as each of you signs the same agreement as the prime minister,
給我完整的控制權
Giving me complete control.
你們決定
Your call.
- 歡迎致電英國特勤局
- 給我接珀加索斯！
- Welcome to British intelligence. - Get me Pegasus!
軍情五處請按1 軍情六處請按2
For MI5, press one. For MI7, press two.
軍情七處 請按3
For MI7, press three.
已獲得8位 G12峰會首腦簽名
Eight G12 signatures now acquired.
通知直升機 這邊快完事兒了
Signal the chopper, we're almost done here.
賬戶服務 請按5
For accounts, press five.
- 兒童托管請按６
- 拜託快點行不！
- For childcare services, press six. - Oh, come on!
更多選項 請按7
For more options, press seven.
什麼？
What?
還需要兩個簽名才能對G12國家數據進行控制
Only two further signatures required to achieve control of G12 national data.
所有英國數據
All UK data
已成功傳輸到 Dot CALM主機
Now successfully transferred to the Dot CALM.
阿芙羅狄蒂 古希臘神話中愛與美的女神
阿芙羅狄蒂請按１珀加索斯請按２
- For Aphrodite, press one. - For Pegasus, press two.
哦 上帝啊
Oh, my god.
準備下潛 重複 準備下潛
Dive the submarine. Repeat, dive the submarine.
- 這裡是主管辦公室
- 我是喬尼·英格力士
Director's office? This is Johnny English.
我需要立刻和珀加索斯通話 事關國家危機！
I need to speak to Pegasus immediately. It's a national emergency!
稍等一下 先生
One moment, please, sir.
這是復仇者潛艇號
This is hms vengeance.
我們有一串啟動碼 重複 啟動代碼已被鎖定
We have a full launch code. Repeat, launch code is locked.
請問我有發射許可嗎？
Do I have your permission to fire?
哦 天吶 請你稍等一下下 拜託
Oh, my god. Could you hold on one moment, please?
長官？長官！
Sir? Sir!
你好？
hello?
在嗎？
Hello?
長官 這裡是復仇者號 我是否被授權發射許可？
Sir! Hms vengeance here. Do I have your permission to launch?
什麼？聽著 我們必須發起攻擊
What? Listen, we have to call in an attack.
你剛才說發起「攻擊」了嗎？長官？
Did you say "attack," sir?
沒錯 發起攻擊 消滅敵人！
Yes! and a Atttack, Atttack!
潛艇所有作戰人員注意！我們要準備發射導彈了
General quarters, we are go for launch.
目標已鎖定！指揮官
Target coordinates locked, commander.
你好？
Hello?
雷嚎？
指揮官 導彈正在重新定向
Commander, the missile is being redirected.
看上去像是鎖定了一個新的敵對目標
It seems to be locking on to a new hostile target.
恍然大悟 √
「果露泉」是什麼？...
What's a "sherbet f"?
- 哦不！
- 那是什麼聲響？
- Oh, no. - What was that?
Dot CALM號已下線 傑森
Dot CALM appears to be offline, Jason.
網絡攻擊已經停止
The cyber attack has been halted.
你有沒...
Did you
距離潛艇很近打電話？
make a call quite close to the submarine, sir?
呃...
Um...
因為...
Because...
你辦到了 長官！
You did it, sir!
任務完成！
Mission accomplished!
沒錯 當然是我啦
Well, exactly!
我在重新評估我們的選項 傑森
I am re-evaluating our options, Jason.
喬尼！喬尼！
Johnny! Johnny!
沃爾塔準備跑路了 他正趕往他的直升機
Volta is getting away! He's heading for his helicopter!
別急 鮑夫
No, bough.
這傢伙是我的！
This one's mine.
小心 長官 小心腳下
Careful, sir. Sir?
看守者感受到了自己體內 榮耀戰魂的力量！... :q
最後兩階台階 長官
Last two steps, sir.
別想溜 沃爾塔！
Not so fast, volta!
我應該被此嚇到嗎 蘭斯洛特爵士？
Is this supposed to scare me, Sir Lancelot?
找好掩護 鮑夫
Take cover, bough.
別擔心 他的槍裡只有六發子彈
Don't worry, he's only got six bullets in that thing.
好吧 那玩意兒本身也能砸人
And, of course, the thing itself.
這些無路可逃了 沃爾塔
You've run out of options, volta.
哦 你還覺得自己贏了是吧？
Oh, you think you've won?
差不多
Mmm.
在我們內華達州的服務器上重新部署攻擊 傑森
Rerouting the attack to our Nevada servers, Jason.
這世界注定要隕落 英格力士 然後我會成為那個笑到最後的人
The world's going down, English. And I'll be the last man standing.
再見 英格力士 拜拜了 互聯網
Goodbye, English! Goodbye, Internet.
我知道了！那是一家 瞪羚341輕型攻擊直升機
I've got it. That's a Gazelle 341 light attack helicopter.
如果我們能黑進它的操作系統 就能禁用它的驅動功能
If we can hack into its operating system, we can disable the drive function.
讓我看看
Here.
瞧瞧你！你想使用你所信賴的東西 但卻又做不到！
Look at you! You couldn't use that thing if your life depended on it!
哈哈...
ha ha ha...
讓我們離開這破地方吧
Let's get outta here.
把這鐵鳥開到...
Get this steel bird in the...
重部署已完成 攻擊程序已安裝在我們位於美帝的服務器農場裡
Rerouting complete. Attack data now installed at our Nevada servers.
我應該發起攻擊嗎？
Should I initiate?
傑森？
Jason?
我應該發起攻擊嗎？
Should I initiate the new attack?
嘗嘗這個！
Initiate this!
傑接姐節結界街潔... 傑森
JJJJJJJJ... Jason.
好吧... 女士們 先生們
Well, uh, ladies and gentlemen.
我想我們都一致同意 那並不是我們原本所期待的那個夜晚
I think we can all agree, that wasn't quite the evening we were expecting.
啊... 啊蛤蛤 蛤蛤
ah ahaha, ahaha...
我原本希望今晚呈現給你們...
I had hoped to present to you tonight...
謝謝你
一個關於未來英國的展望
A vision of what britain might be.
但 正如所發生的一般 一個男人將我們所有人從這個夜晚拯救了出來...
But, as it happens, the man who saved us all this evening,
這個男人 也許我該補充一點 是我十分信任 親自指派負責這次的事件
the man who, I might add, I personally assigned to this case,
也另闢蹊徑地為我們呈現了 另一種與眾不同的願景
has presented us with a different kind of vision.
一個生動活現的英國優良品質化身 如果你允許我這麼說
A living embodiment, if you like, of those fundamental British qualities
這些品質確保了我們所心愛的國家能夠長久地繁榮昌盛
that have ensured that our beloved island nation endures.
赴湯蹈火的勇氣 無窮無盡的足智多謀
Courage under fire, endless ingenuity
在這一切之上 是一種低調而又——
and above all, a quiet
堅不可摧的人格尊嚴
unassailable dignity.
你們是魔鬼嗎！？... |･ω･『)
多謝啦
Thank you.
歡迎回來 英格力士先生
Welcome back, Mr. English.
多謝你 校長
Thank you, headmaster.
感謝你願意參加我們的客座演講
Thank you for agreeing to be our guest speaker.
現在州長和工作人員都在花園那邊等我們
Now the governors and staff are all waiting for us in the rose garden.
好的 不過請你稍微給我幾分鐘 校長
Yes, if you could just excuse me for a few minutes, headmaster.
好吧
oh
早安 先生！早安！
Morning, sir! Hello, sir!
歡迎回來 老師！
Welcome back, sir!
驚喜不？
Surprise!
謝謝你們
Thank you.
話說 斯特雷克那小子呢？
Where's straker?
- 在這兒先生
- 好極
- Here, sir. - Good.
以及你在這兒 巴格利
And, of course, baggaley.
That was very good. Very good.
沒事兒 真的很棒 所有人 聚過來
All right, gather round, everyone. Gather round.
我給你們帶了些秘密♂玩具
I've got some toys to show you.
好 放心看吧
Ooh! There we go.
我們有 這個 還有這個
There we are. There we are.
- 麵包棒吹管誰想試試？
- 我！
- Breadstick blowpipe, anyone? - Me!
就決定是你啦
There you go.
蘋果手雷？
Granny Smith hand grenade?
- 那麼絞殺手錶呢？
- 老師４７該換新的了
- And what about a garroting watch? - Here, sir.
拿好了
There you go.
這個 還是讓我來保管吧
Here, let me take that.
別擔心 只是種輕微鎮靜劑
Don't worry, it's only a mild sedative.
哦！那是根拔開後五秒就會爆炸的保險絲
Oh! That's just a five-second fuse.
行了行了 別耍了 小心47叔叔來找你
Yes, all right, we all know what garroting looks like.
你準備好了嗎 英格力士先生？
Whenever you're ready, Mr. English.
哦 抱歉 校長 我一分鐘內就好
Oh, I'm sorry, headmaster, I'll just be one moment.
- 收好那些好的
- 哦！
- Just take those. Thank you. - Ooh!
讓我們把這些收起來吧 就像這樣...
Put those away, shall we? There we...
呃...
Um...
我一直很喜歡果凍軟糖！... :q
I always did love a jelly baby.